World building is one of the most
important concepts in modern marketing
because the world of identity and media
has radically changed over the last
decade. [music] Marketing used to assume
a communication between the buyer and
the seller, which made sense for a
single transaction. But increasingly,
products [music] are sold on identity.
Worldbuing treats everyone like they're
a character in a brand's movie. [music]
And that's just not you viewing that
brand's film. You're a participant in
it. We're all actors in their world.
We're using their props. We're shaping
what that story looks like. It's [music]
fun, it's compelling, and it works. But
how do you actually do this? So, in this
video, Scott and I are going to go
through brand examples, principles from
both brand building and from film to
share the process, share examples, share
things that we've worked on and things
we respect that can help you really
understand world building. Let's lock
in. So, when we talk about world
building, there's a brand that never
ceases to come up and that brand is
vacation. And so, I know you have a
relationship there. You understand the
brand. Talk to me a bit about that.
What's your history with them? And let's
dive into it. I'm very fortunate to be
an adviser and an investor in vacation
which is how I got to know them. Um and
even before then was a fan.
>> What struck me from the beginning is uh
is the setting right it is it's a world
and I believe that that concept of
setting is important to understand in
context of world building. Yeah. What
are your thoughts there? What do you
think of that setting they've built
>> to understand the setting of vacation?
Let's understand the psychology first of
the category. Right. So sunscreen,
right? That was that was one of their
first products and that's what the brand
is known for. And sunscreen has changed
a lot over the last 50 years.
>> True. Yeah.
>> So sunscreen used to be about fun in the
sun. It used to be about play. It used
to be about the beach. It used to be
about togetherness. Kind of having a
wild time. And then sunscreen became
about health and safety. And it became
clinical. It became about protection, UV
radiation, the fear and the efficacy,
right? That all took over the sunscreen
category. And then like so many
categories, it was upgraded and brands
traded up into beauty. So, how do you
make the package smaller? How do you
make the margins bigger? How do you sell
it in more and more fancy doors? and how
do you put it in a really slick looking
package that almost becomes part of your
skinincare routine versus going out into
the wild and having fun in the sun and
vacation asked well what would it look
like to make sunscreen fun again and
represent that fun in the sun and so the
world of vacation the setting that
they've built is to transport you to the
time when sunscreen was about having fun
and so they made a whole bunch of
creative decisions to transport port you
to that setting visually, aesthetically
with photographs. It lives in this kind
of dreamlike world from the late '7s to
the late8s where there was club med and
digital cameras weren't something that
everyone carried around. Cameras were
something you take on vacation and you'd
shoot a lot of photos where you wanted
to have memories. And so the brand world
of vacation is very much rooted in
vacation photography from middle-class
Americans that are going down to the
Caribbean or down to the Gulf Coast,
right? Or hanging out in San Diego. One
of my favorite thinkers, investors,
Charlie Mer has this quote, take
something and take it seriously. And
world building is all about taking it
really seriously.
>> They took it extremely seriously. So,
you could take something and say, "Okay,
well, we're going to we're going to use
a little bit of inspiration from
packaging in the '7s or the '8s, but of
course, like we're going to have a
modern website and we're going to, you
know, print the packing slip with a
normal font or really just think through
one element of it." But what vacation
does is no, no, no, how do we take this
to an 11 out of 10 in in terms of
transportive world building? And so, for
instance, one of the ways they did that
was they found someone's Flickr profile,
a uh a dad who had taken photos of his
family on vacation through the 80s and
'9s and happened to scan them and upload
them to Flickr. And they ended up
licensing that material, that
photography, so that they weren't just
using AI or trying to recreate, you
know, slick photo shoots, but origin of
the brand. They said, "How do we
actually take this family that had
documented their vacations and make that
part of our lore and build our visuals
around that?" So, they had this whole
mosaic of visual material to work from
and layer on.
>> And I love that uh that idea of taking
it seriously across everything is really
important. I remember one of the most
interesting things I felt they did was
when they launched in Target, you saw
all even the Target advertisements still
lived 100% within that world. Taking
something that seriously is something so
few brands are like willing to
participate in. I feel like that's
what's required to build as we're
talking about.
>> Exactly. Because in a movie, you have
great actors who are character actors or
method actors, right? Method actors,
they don't break character when the
director says cut. They keep it going
and they commit to the bit. And
worldbuilding brands commit to the bit.
>> I agree. And I like uh the example of
pulling from that Flickr account is a
good example. This idea of citizens of a
brand's world. Okay, we are whether
we're a consumer, whether it's an
influencer, whether it's a founder,
member of the brand, there are people
that exist within that. I would love to
hear your thoughts on that concept.
>> Well, traditional brands will grow by
distribution. They'll grow by promotion.
Worldbuilding brands build by
initiation. They grow through inviting
people to be members of that story and
members of cast members of that movie.
And so to use vacation as an example
again, they made a really important
creative choice at the very beginning
around their email list because when you
sign up for a brand's email list, you
get an email that says, "Are you sure
you want to opt into what might be years
and years of spam in the future
>> 15% off?" Yeah, exactly.
>> And so what vacation did was, you know,
instead of subscribe to our email list,
they said, "Well, do you want to be a
junior executive in the vacation
corporation?" And if you want to be a
corporation, sign up for your summer job
here. You put your email in, put your
name in, and not only do you get an
email saying you're on the list, but you
got a business card, an image, a JPEG of
a business card that had a randomly
determined title of your functional role
as an executive in the vacation
corporation. So, I'm the head of
nautical matters. Some people are shrimp
boat captain architects. other ones are
inflatable pool toy mechanics. And so
everyone has this kind of mad lib title
of what they exist in the in the
vacation story. And so that gives people
now permission to play the role even
further. So you'll find people
commenting on their LinkedIn posts about
well as the junior executive responsible
for my Thai concoctions, I for one am
really happy with this new product
introduction. And on the other hand, in
terms of committing to the bit,
vacation, they don't just communicate
like a brand in the normal world. They
very much tongue-in-cheek on a 10 out of
10 basis communicate as the quote world
famous vacation corporation. And they
exist at a time in the 80s when
corporate was cool, right? The Patrick
Baitman uh calling card and the the the
rise and the ascent of the Yepy. Since
then, corporate isn't cool anymore.
People don't want to work in offices.
They don't want to work in cubicles,
right? It's all counterculture.
Everyone's got their side hustle. The
vacation again transport you back to a
world where the HR department wasn't
trying to be cool and hip and they're
communicating in very technical
corporate language that becomes
highensity. It becomes funny because at
the end of the day, you have these two
polar opposites. a very serious buttoned
up formal corporation that is all about
fun in the sun.
>> I think uh from brands often look at
something like vacation and they go
there's no way we could build that we
couldn't go all in. They've already
taken that '8s idea and I think one of
the first exercises is just looking at
that vernacular right what that exercise
the first email does is it points you
into all the words that build the brands
shrimp captain pool toys etc. I feel
like almost any niche can be in that. I
look at um my my friends at Air did
something similar like a generator. You
could put your picture in, it would give
you a meme, but it was in their
language. All the language of creative
direction and people that are like
overly online or have that ambiguous
income job, etc. because that's a lot of
their uh their actual like consumer base
is in these sort of ambiguous creative
jobs. I do think that like one of those
exercises just going through every one
of these like ideas and concepts and
words behind it and defining those words
for a brand is like so much more
important than whatever's in the brand
guide, right? The quote unquote. It's
like what do we really think about that?
How do we really look at that? And you
to segue this a bit when people go,
"Okay, well, how do I find inspiration?
How do I actually hunt that down? How do
I begin to have it from from a brand?"
All this is really just taking these
principles from film, right? Like the
movie uh analogy is a good one because
it's so accurate. It's also where we
draw a lot from. I'd be curious um like
to talk about a bit about where those
rootings in world building come from
when it comes to movies, film and
action.
>> Yeah. Well, world building comes from
cinema and cinema is this beautiful rich
visual auditory kind of social construct
that's all around story. And we'll talk
about story, but I think one of the best
worldbuilders in cinema, not the first,
but I think one of the most beloved and
one of the most current is Wes Anderson.
Of course, he's really famous for his
world building. And so as an example
here, my favorite Wes Anderson film is
Grand Budapest Hotel. Uh Grand Budapest
Hotel is a a masterwork in so many
different ways. And so the question for
us today is well, what separates simply
good art direction, right? Like you'll
see in a film like The Substance from
World building. And what what Wes
Anderson does is borrow a lot from
children's literature and different
mechanisms where he goes beyond simply
the idea of setting to think about
institutions. Okay?
>> So he shows institutions in his films.
In the case of uh Moonrise Kingdom, it's
the khaki scouts, not the Boy Scouts.
And that that little kind of concession
there of taking something from the
normal world, right, the world that we
all live in, like the Boy Scouts, and
just tweaking it a little bit and making
a slightly fictionalized version of it
makes it just enough real, but also just
enough kind of fantasy to really work in
a worldbuing setting. So, if we take
Grand Budapest Hotel for example,
there's a um a a fictional country
called Zabrovka. And Zabrovka is like
this amalgamation of an Alpine central
European country. It's part of the
Austrohungarian Empire. It's a little
bit of the Czech Republic. It's a little
bit of Austria. It's a little bit of
Hungary. Uh and it's an imagined
institution, right? This idea of that
part of Europe at the time. And then you
take the Grand Budapest Hotel itself.
There are these imperial hotels that
were built in kind of spa towns in that
empire. And you know as soon as you see
it that this institution existed for the
film, it's going to exist after the
film. And then institutions within that
like Mendele's Bakery, right? The story
bakery that takes place in it or uh
instead of the SS, it's the zigzag, the
zz, right? We're sort of just mirroring
that little icon that goes on the
soldiers um gle. So these are things
that build story for for Wes Anderson
these films. The other thing that he
does is the ability to go really really
tight on props. So every object is a
representation of this world when you
zoom in on it really quickly. Whether
it's a matchbook, whether it's a menu
item, it has all the details of that
world that allow you to place yourself
in it. And I think that's an important
kind of item for brand building because
when you are a brand building or when
you're a world building brand, you
create essentially props in this movie
that you're creating and you've got to
pay attention to those little
>> and they don't often like don't take
them seriously enough, right? There's
just, you know, oh, it's the average,
it's your koozie, it's your holder, and
people talk about merch, but there's a
real conversation around that. I mean,
uh, Palunteer, for better or for worse,
has, uh, gotten a significant amount of
conversation around releasing a French
chore coat, a street wear drop, but
they're building artifacts, right? And I
I can I like the idea of artifacts from
a film as the same as artifacts of a
brand, but they're almost more important
because you have so few actual touch. If
you're going to spend the $2 or put have
the website like vacation does, it's
important.
>> Yeah. The artifacts and the totems,
right? The like the design to the extent
that every single object, every detail
of it, right? Like this kind of baroque
ornate 80s down to the gold foil
reflectivity which is is is go, right?
and over the top, but that's the point
because it fits into that world.
>> And you even see that even you go into
the Sephora merchandising and you'll see
the same thing or, you know, Ulta,
wherever they are, you'll see like every
one of those displays as an extension. I
love that a lot about what Vacation's
done.
>> Extrapolating this to any company,
right? Like product companies, consumers
companies work great, but really any
type of company is you've got to
remember that human beings make meaning
and organize everything through stories.
We are the only species do this is
understand and have the logic that
defines our life is through stories. Not
facts, not evidence or data but stories
because stories is how we make sense of
things like morality and identity uh and
challenge and relationships. And so what
brands do is they hijack the neural
circuitry that was developed for human
beings to relate to each other with
stories and translate it into what
they're trying to achieve with their
brand and their growth. And what a story
is in the most fundamental level is a
character, a hero who encounters a
crisis or a challenge and through that
challenge becomes transformed to become
a better version of themselves.
>> Hero's journey.
>> The hero's journey. And what brands do
is they sell a better version of
yourself, a better version of the hero.
And so the question is how are you
transformed through this journey? And
what worldbuilding brands do is they put
you as most of the time the hero in that
journey and they show an incredible
level of cinematic detail that is highly
evocative and plays on your imagination
of what do I look and feel like when I'm
transformed by this product. So today,
we're going to add a real skill to your
toolkit in 120 seconds. Brought to you
by Framer. Every time a consumer clicks
on an ad or goes to download your ebook
or to book a call on your website,
they're hitting a funnel, landing page,
and pages after that. And most suck.
They're not building your brand's world.
One of the highest value skills you can
do as a creative is to be able to
improve this funnel to build it because
that drives more sales, more email subs,
and when you can quantify the work, you
get paid more for it. Framer is a
complete website platform and I love it
for quickly being able to spin up brand
assets like this especially for software
services and personal brand sites. And
today I want to talk about the new frame
agents and the workflow to create new
sites and sections of sites. So here
this entire site that you see was
generated by framework agents. I gave it
a reference bento style layout like
this. Some of my links and imagery and a
picture of myself to create and it made
this for me. I did not design anything.
I was able to go in and edit those call
to actions. And what I just asked for,
you can see here on the right, was for
it to give me a placeholder section for
testimonials and for FAQ. And it gives
it to me in mobile and on desktop. I can
preview it right here. I've asked for
special effects for the rollovers. You
can adjust. I'm doing all of this.
Everything you see here was created in
chat with framer agents. And all this
matches the design style of my website
overall. So if you're building this, you
want to start with a landing page. The
sections you want to call out to have
are an aggressive title with a subtitle.
anchor that in your customer painoint,
your core section, the header you saw
there, where you can put the value
propositions of what you're trying to
get. Ideally, a video about the product
offer if you have one, and the ability
to sign up or act on the offer right
there, the way you saw with my form. And
ideally, all that is above the fold.
They see that right when they land on
the website. And then below it, you can
get into testimonials and proof points,
dive into the top features, more video
or graphic examples, UGC testimonials,
big call to action to act now, and then
a frequently asked question section to
really get to any reason they might have
an objection. That's a great landing
page structure to use. But then if
you're booking a call or even someone
buys something from there, the
confirmation page they get is ultra
important because it can radically
increase the chance of conversion on a
call or even upsell another product. I'd
be putting a personal video from the CEO
or a freelancer there along with a
personal message and what they can
expect next. Doesn't have to be
high-res. It can just be a yap. But
literally take that outline for this
page, drop it into framer with the
agents and ask it to make those sections
with placeholder copy you can update or
ask it to generate initial copy or bring
in copy that you've already done and
have it make the complete site. You can
polish your drafts, refine your design.
I started that whole bento layout just
from a screenshot of a similar site. And
ask for little world building elements.
They go a long way. Photos or design
that tie to your social media, video
embeds, stickers with your logo
elements, websites or extensions of your
brand story. And you can just ask for
them in chat with Framer. Ship your
sites faster with Framer today and use
code orin for 30% off of Framer Pro
annual plan. Link is in the description.
>> This is actually a good time to bring up
your background. My worldbuing resume
starts with Sir Kenszington's which is
the company that I founded and what Sir
Kensington's was was reimagining
condiments. So we actually started the
brand and the world before we even made
the first product. And the way it
started was the idea that there are so
many different types of mustards out
there and there's only one type of
ketchup. And the type of ketchup that's
out there is obviously dominated by
Hind. And then every other brand is in
the same package with the same product
inside and the same texture. And it's
ubiquitous, but it's not really saying
anything interesting. But at the same
time, ketchup as an absolute strangle
hold on the American refrigerator,
right? It's in like 98% of American
refrigerators. And Hines is a is a is a
call brand, right, that everyone knows,
almost like a Kleenex. Um, and so we
realized that if we were to just simply
make a better product, we would fail
because it wouldn't capture anyone's
attention. So we said, let's do the
exact opposite of Hines, right? If Hines
is going to be in plastic, we're going
to start in glass. If Hines is
indiscriminately squeezed, we are going
to be scooped like a high-end European
>> I love that dichotomy. Look at what's
happening in the market. Okay, how do we
elevate or do the opposite? It's a great
way to look at things.
>> Do the opposite. And and if Hines is
Americana and synonymous with the
roadside diner and fast food and like
really central to America, well, what's
the opposite of that?
>> Let's be English, right? And how do we
be English? Well, we needed to create a
a lore that basically was drafting off
of heritage that we were inventing cuz
we didn't have heritage. The product was
brand new. We were kids in college at
the time.
>> You guys weren't in the
>> witch and start chefs or anything like
that. And so we committed to the bit and
we built a a a brand of 11 out of 10
intensity on that method acting. So we
created this elaborate story before we
even made our first jar of ketchup. Sir
Kensington himself went to Cambridge for
undergrad and Oxford for graduate school
and he did a treatise for the queen in
Constantinople on Ionian chutneys and
spice sauces and worked among the spice
traders of the Bosphorus. He returns to
England knowing that he cannot alone
make sauces as a way to make his fortune
and so he has the brilliant idea who is
insuring the insurance companies. I'm
going to start the first reinsurance
company to ensure insurance companies in
this sort of loop. Uh he does very
financially well on that. And of course
he doesn't just retire and kick back. He
says, "I'm going to gather the greatest
creative minds in Europe create a salon
series." He hosts salons at his country
estate. In one of these salons,
Katherine the Great of Russia is in
attendance. The emperor of Japan has
also made the trip across the ocean and
has brought a cut of Kobe. hitherto
never tasted in United Kingdom. And of
course, Katherine the Great of Russia
says, "Well, I would like to try this
coobe beef. Do you have any ketchup to
pair it with?" Sir Kensington thinking
to himself, "I can't serve a Zarus high
fructose corn syrup and something that I
just bought at the local supermarket. I
need to make something better." So, he
goes in the kitchen, pulls the tomatoes
together, pulls the raw sugar, finds a
malt vinegar, and concocts on the spot
Sir Kenzing's ketchup for her to try.
>> I love that the lore is just off the top
of the head. Let's go. Yeah.
>> And it changes every time I tell it. I
think that what's really important here
is what you're hearing is play. This was
not we need to turn the business around.
This was not we need to get in a
whiteboard and figure out what Q2 is
going to look like. We had no idea that
this would actually ever be a business.
We were in play because storytelling and
world building is play. And you've got
to be able to get yourself in that
mental space.
>> And I think um I'm I'm curious how that
permeated culture of the company
>> to start like with that culture. We did
create this this this lore and almost
these artifacts if you will. And so, for
instance, when we launched, we made we
worked with a a a wonderful artist in
New York um named Eric Adolfson to
sketch and draw all of the various
vessels that Sir Kensington's attempted
before, you know, uh stabilizing on this
ketchup jar and all of the different
circumstances that you could use the
condiment in, right? This really deep
level of detail. And for the for the
company culture, um, we really thought
about the mission to bring integrity and
charm, ordinary and overlooked. And
you'll see here, we gave everyone this
this steel tablet, right? Again, the
sort of lore almost like a set of
commandments,
>> not not a 4x6 card, you know, a steel
tablet,
>> something that has real physicality to
it. And the language that had this
internal voice and consistency. So,
integrity and charm, right? These are
words that have a kind of a subtle
English almost aristocratic feel to
them, like they f sound like they came
out of eaten. And one of the other great
rules of of branding is humanize. Always
humanize. And so, in the character of
Sir Kensington, you have the the
personification of integrity and charm.
And you have integrity and charm as the
watchwords in our mission. And then
beyond that, culturally, we as the team
members were the acolytes and the
students of Sir Kensington. And so when
we would go to a trade show or when we
would go on a sales call, I had a
mustache for seven years of my life just
as Sir Kensington did. And we would wear
suits, dark suits with ties because take
something and take it seriously, right?
And I think if I have one regret, it's I
didn't take it too seriously. We didn't
take it seriously for long enough.
>> Yeah. I think that's what's interesting
is like how do you grow with that? you
know, someone like vacation is just
embodied for so long. As you begin to
get a company and you have outside sales
reps and oh, we now we're in Australia
and they're like, how do you kind of
keep that going? I think is uh is yeah
interesting challenge.
>> Yeah. And I think that's the challenge
of the artist, right? That's the
challenge of the artist. I like to use
this model that, you know, an artist is
known for expressing themselves and
telling their story with no definition
of success beyond that. It's not about
how how much you sell, right? It's not
about how you change the world. It's
really about self-expression. And then
on the very very end of that you have a
hack, right? Someone who is only doing
something as a jo o someone who's doing
something simply to solve a problem. And
in the middle you have craft. A craft
person is expressing themselves and
they're putting in the care of an artist
but they're delivering the function of a
job to be done. And so that's the
question is how do you find the right
balance of craft? because you've seen
and we've all seen so many brands that
are these beautiful artistic expressions
that are dedicated to these things, but
the commercial element, the job they're
doing for the customer isn't satisfied.
Exactly.
>> And the story isn't legible, right? And
then we also see lots of products that
are there to make a buck, right, and
check all the boxes and those don't last
either. And so the question is, how do
you figure out what do you listen to?
Because it is important, right, to talk
about your organic bonafides. It is
important to make sure that you put the
right features and benefits on your
Amazon page for all the different kind
of practical matters of someone buying
ketchup online, right? And so I think if
anything we were pushed a little bit
more towards the blander side of things.
If I were to go back in time, we would
have committed to the bit a little bit
harder.
>> And I love that it was rooted in the
shelf, right? Uh I think that's a great
thing for anyone working on something
like this to look at is like what
actually happens on the shelf in your
category. So, even with sunscreen, like
you look at people that are thriving in
sunscreen, look at someone like Kosas
who took uh okay, it's it's skincare and
it's sunscreen at the same time. It's
Sunbum, they're living inside a surf.
It's Super Goop, they've gone all in on
the ingredients. It's vacation, they've
gone on the lifestyle. All those brands
are disruptors in their space because
they looked at a boring shelf and said,
"We have an angle." Same thing with what
you talked about in food. And a shelf
can mean a physical shelf if you're
actually in retail, but also if it's
look, if it's AP software, it's just you
how do you have a perspective inside
what those other ones are are looking at
is more tech enabled? What world can you
build? And I think that rooting whatever
world you build inside a position
saying, hey, we're going to be the
opposite of the diner ketchup is an
important way to actually tie it to that
the jo end, the value end, the the list
on the Amazon.
>> Yes. And I think one one way to do that
and and what we did was recognize that
because Newan knew who we were, we
needed something that was so weird and
different on shelf that someone would
have to do a double take.
>> Yeah. It was impactful. I remember that
was my like initial experience with
this. You're like, "Wait, you got what?"
And it cost how much? And that thing and
it's that's a great there's very little
conversations you have around ketchup,
right? And to be seen is to be sold. And
so that similarly whether it is um you
know vacation sunscreen or sir
Kensington's going back to the Wes
Anderson aesthetic of the matchbook
right and the dedication to detail. It's
when you are creating a product that is
going to sit on shelf. How do you make
it abundantly clear that this is a prop
that belongs in a different world and
the world that you've built? And then
when you use the prop, what I love most
about this is like I've pulled this out
of a beach bag and people comment on it.
Whether they know the brand, someone
knows the brand like, "Oh, is that
vacation?" If they don't know the brand,
they're like, "Oh, is that like some
aloha like back in the day like Hawaii?"
And then it's immediately you are the
owner of the artifact. You're in that
brand film like we talked about before.
And it comes and it's just as simple as
a package.
>> You are you are initiated and you are
now a junior executive in the Asian
Corporation.
>> Um,
>> so the prop the prop attitude is really
important. And I think what's
interesting is when you see this go even
further, right? And so I want to talk
about Ralph Lauren because they're
they've built now many Wolves, right?
You see a brand that has gone from they
they stand for so many things for the
American West, they stand for the Ivy
League, they're the Olympic
representative of America, there's
purple label subbrands. And so the
brands actually build this out so much
into uh and you see it in everything
from cafes to clothing. That's where it
takes on almost a new life of its own. I
have a great appreciation for those
brands. Uh, and I guess I'm I'm curious
what are like how do you feel about that
brand? How do you feel about actually
extending that world beyond? You know,
you built a brand in a category. If you
had to build greater than that, what's
the ideas and playbook there?
>> Yeah. Well, clothing and apparel and
fashion is such rich territory for this
because clothing is is our costume,
right? It's the number one way where we
can immediately express our identity to
friends and strangers and how people see
us and it gives us the confidence or the
attitude for what we want to project,
right? And so costume is like quite
literally part of the cinematic
experience. And I think especially call
it like in an urban setting, right? in a
city. When you walk out of your
apartment, no matter what your apartment
looks like, if you're in New York City,
you know, how small it is, how grungy it
is, when you go outside, you become part
of the city, right? And you become
characters in that city with this
costume. And this, I think, goes back
to, you know, the late 19th century
France and kind of the um the the the
development of this cosmopolitan culture
and urban culture, right, through the
20s and beyond. And so Ralph Lauren is
of course a, you know, it's a it's a
it's a storied and beautiful example
that isn't just one world, but it's a
world of worlds because Ralph Lauren has
the New England prep and it also has the
the rugged wild west. And where and why
I think this works going back to the
idea of the transformed individual,
right? And what you become through the
the transformation of participating and
enrolling in a brand is about fantasy.
and Ralph Lauren in their world of the
prep aesthetic, it sells a fantasy of
unearned privilege and elegance and
being able to be included in any room,
right? And when you think about going
back to storytelling, fundamental human
psychology and neurosircuitry, the most
important thing that we can do every day
is make sure that we are not severed
from society and that we are not mocked,
that we are included, that we are
participating, that we will find a mate,
that we will procreate, that we will be
respected in the community. And when you
draft off of waspy American culture that
was at the top of society right at that
time and all the tropes of that
aesthetic, you can live into the fantasy
of being high status in included and of
having this unearned privilege that
people fantasize about. Similarly, in
the American West, right, is the other
side of the country. It's a different
fantasy, but it's a fantasy about
freedom. It's a fantasy about being able
to self-express in nature to some
extent, but still connected and
respected in society in kind of a
maverick rugged way, an individualist
way, where the prep aesthetic is all
about a uh cohesive community and kind
of a societal acceptance way. So,
there's these different psychologies
going on, but they all kind of
fundamentally go back to the fantasy of
identity and of social inclusion. And
what's interesting is you would put
those if we were in a vacuum and you
were talking about the American West,
we're talking about the Ivy League prep,
it wouldn't make sense that they would
live in one category, one world of
worlds under a brand, but that
throughine of Americana of that like
ideal like uh is so kind of excellently
executed throughout that brand. What
what I find interesting, I want to dive
into some of these worlds in particular
is is like their appeal. So for
instance, like the Western world, uh the
idea of the Wild West, the idea of
freedom, that's as big in Japan. And
Japan has co-opted so much of they make
better kind of Americana western wear
than America does at this point. It's
equally as fascinating from Australia to
Europe. The concept of Texas. There's
these ideas that are just so much bigger
than the brand itself you can jump into.
I feel oddly the same way we saw with
whether it was Sporty and Rich
immediately took that into a you know
like a a modern female at the point in
time when they were at their peak.
There's all these little ways to kind of
co-opt it. What what other worlds are
there out there? What are those other
things that you know people can tap
into? You did that a bit with
aristocracy. Uh, we've seen it with kind
of 80s and nostalgia. I think it'd be
cool to basically put some ideas out
there for people that they could tap in.
>> Yeah. I mean, I would say like it's kind
of whatever you fantasize about and
whatever has the depth of a world. I
mean, let's take a let's take sort of a
left turn here and talk about the brand
Andre. Yeah. Call a brand. It's a
company, right? And is a um a defense
tech company, right? It's a new defense
tech company started by the founder of
Oculus. And most defense tech companies,
right, they don't actually want to be
seen by the outside world. Like United
Technologies, what do they make? Bombs,
[laughter] right? Like, and but and what
Andrew does is Andrew has realized that
wait a minute, there is a fantasy of
American technological superiority that
wasn't really being told. And when you
have the rank and file members of the
Pentagon and the government that now
grew up on first person shooter video
games and the world of video games and
the the internet, then how do you build
an aesthetic world for them, right? And
so the choices that Andrew has made
about how they design their products
with like the matte black, the sans
Sarah fonts, the art direction that they
that they put in. They are selling a
fantasy of American technological
superiority that goes beyond the messy
elements of the battlefield and the the
the difficult procurement process of of
of government contracting into this very
pure world that people can fantasize
about and and that relates to American
pride.
>> And even the artifacts you can buy the
the metallic alloys, same thing they use
to make whatever space inside a Game
Boy.
together. The mod retro in I think it's
Titanium, the Andre edition mod retro is
exactly that is we are going to pair
this idea of a of a video game with
ballistic missiles, right? And with this
intelligent technology. And that's
perfect for an era where we are now in
point-and-click warfare, right? with the
the drones and the technology that we
have right now in the Gulf. Um it is
point-and-click warfare that is directly
related to that lore of video games.
>> Well, it's also it's continuing a lore.
Um people always look at oh well you
have your United Industries or someone
who can't talk about anything, but
there's also a lot of lore inside
infrastructure, science, government
propaganda. You look at NASA and like
the the the craziest brand guide ever
and the most licensing possibly done
that's done to get a it's HR. It's we're
recruiting by getting people excited
about science by putting these things
out there that you can then treat as you
know again artifacts. Uh and I think
even with defense we look at skunk works
and these things that kind of happened
in the past they were more
tongue-in-cheek and they just adapted
that to to the modern age. But I do
encourage you know whether you are a uh
fan of the industrial world complex or
not. The idea of looking at any single
niche you look at, there is that way to
attract people's excitement about it by
finding a world that you know your your
target industry loves those people are
had you had some moments with. Like a
game boy is a connection point to a uh
like a a defense company is really about
the kind of people that are who have had
that childhood chose to pursue that into
engineering want to connect all those
dots together. It's built a world for
them.
>> I got another one for you. Let's go.
I've been thinking about. So, a lot of a
lot of ink has been spilled about the
Japanese imagination of America and
workware and denim and rockabilly,
right? And what we're seeing now,
especially recently, is the American
imagination of Japan.
>> Interesting.
>> And so, if you think about obviously
it's an Australian brand, but an Asop
store, the interior of an Asop store is
minimalist, but with organic materials
and textures.
>> It's a western interpretation of Japan.
All that. Yeah. and or District Vision
who just opened a shop a few blocks from
here with that is very much inspired by
Japanese minimalist design and with
materials and plant life and lighting.
Uh and then again this is a Japanese
brand but it has taken hold in the west
is Snow Peak. Yeah. Right. Snow Peak is
a brand that represents not performance
in nature or domination over nature, but
a Japanese concept of coexistence with
nature. And Snow Peak has the materials.
They have a what they call, I think, a a
campsite or a a a campland up in, you
know, Washington State that that you can
go to and visit as a physical place.
They have stores and all of these these
little artifacts that they make are
beautifully mil and machined in that
level of Japanese craft detail for the
outdoors. And they play into the western
fantasy of a simpler minimalistic life
that has more that has less stuff but
better stuff which is in the you know
world of wash and teu and Amazon and
Walmart. We have like too much stuff and
we need to go back to those middle
roots. I think uh I I think there's a
lot of conversation around running
brands like Satisfy etc. and not nearly
enough around District Vision because I
think District Vision is a fascinating
brand and I'm a was a big kind of early
consumer of it because they really have
that mission and methodology kind of
locked. It's for mindful athletes. It's
based in like meditation practice at the
beginning. Uh and you look at a lot of
brands try to find how can I attach this
to something bigger has more meaning in
life. How do I make a mission statement
mean something people actually care
about? And they're a great example of a
brand that really rooted it in that
because not only is it just saying this
is for mindful athletes, hey, here's the
meditation thing you can purchase from
us. Here's the program you can buy into.
When you go on our brand trip, you're
going to a center for, you know,
establishing whatever it is about your
your inner journey. There are very few
examples of people really have that
mission that's actually rooted in
anything serious. I think they're
they're a good one for
>> Yeah. And where that I mean where that
comes from and you know people talk
about authenticity, a word that gets
bandied about, right? Well, what does
that mean? And art art and craft is a
self-expression, right? And some of my
favorite brands are self-expressions of
founders and artists. And so, yeah, when
you when we talk about how to
practically apply these, it's not really
going to work if it's not kind of deeply
inside of you, right? So, I am an
anglophile. I love to perform. So for me
the sir Kensington character and the
world was like living out a personal
fantasy and a personal belief. Similarly
like the two founders of district vision
this is not something that they are like
putting on a spreadsheet and saying what
do we do next? It's this is an intuitive
feel for them right and it is in some
ways like the gift that they have to
give. Um, similarly with vacation,
right? It's about it is about community
and is about taking kind of a world that
the fun has been drained out of and
figuring out like how do we inject fun
back into this world and take it really
seriously.
>> If you want to get practical with this,
uh, you had this idea called the hotel
test. What is the hotel test?
>> Well, the hotel test is if you could
imagine your brand, whatever brand
you're working on as a hotel. First of
all, is it easy to imagine or is it hard
to imagine? Right? Like if I want to
imagine Hyundai as a hotel, I don't get
a lot of detail.
>> Zoho. Yeah.
>> But if I want to imagine Ferrari as a
hotel, I know exactly what that hotel
looks and feels like, right? Great
worldbuilding brands pass the hotel
test. As a great exercise, I'd say, what
is the hotel for your brand? When you
walk into the lobby, what does it smell
like? What does it look and feel like?
When you're meet greeted at the front
desk, how is the the attendant dressed?
How do they greet you? What's the
language that they use? When you go up
to your room, what's the music that's
playing in the elevator? What's waiting
for you on your pillow? When you go into
the bathroom, what type of soap is
there? Right? And when you leave, what
type of little trinket do they give you
on the way out? You know, what does the
key card look like? If you can build the
details in the hotel test, then that's a
great entree. into world building and
even if it's not for like rebranding
your entire company and rebranding your
brand, treat it as a we're going to do a
campaign around this. We're we're going
to take we're going to take this hotel
test and we're going to funnel into a
campaign which is just exactly the same
way that what artists do with album
releases, right? Think about each Kanye
album, right, has a different structure
and look and feel. And sometimes it's
transparent and sometimes it uses
photography and sometimes it uses bright
colors and sometimes it uses handwritten
scroll.
>> It signals an error.
>> It signals an error, right? And so
campaigns can be the exact same way.
>> I like with the hotel test is okay.
First you need to define it yourself.
You need to understand what the brand
stands for. And then it's how do you get
your customer to be able to say that
same answer back to you or them to be
able to picture in the mind the way you
and I were both able to picture a very
similar Ferrari. Yeah. Uh, and I like to
think of too in the influence world, uh,
the idea of like the brand trip test I
think is an interesting extension of
that too because you want to define,
okay, if you have all these experiences,
but now who are the people if they were
if they were on this trip, who would
they be, what activities would they be
doing? Like what would they be posting?
Who would be viewing it? And would
people care? And begin to build that
out. And I could see um people use ramp
as an example a lot because obviously
they're a one of the few companies in a
boring industry that's done some real
world building but there's the ordinary
there's a few that have kind of built
outside of their niche and you can do
this in anything whether you are doing
that as a hedge fun whether you are
doing that as venture capital whether
you're doing as a microphone company I
think there is the ability to conduct
like both of those tests and think about
what they say is a is a powerful vehicle
um any parting thoughts that you want to
leave anyone with
>> take something and take it seriously
commit to the bit and have fun with it.
Absolutely. I appreciate you coming and
talking through it and uh we will we'll
link more information about Scott in the
description. We'll cover all the world
building below. I appreciate you guys
sitting with us and walking through it.
Thank you.